原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     小酸奶  Silence  我有貓我驕傲
翻譯     學術男優  一只蝦  DustD
校對     蘇小黛
時間軸     啾啾  大蔥
后期     8T
總監     蘇小黛
前情提要
-你干了什么  凱蒂  -都結束了  所以不重要了
- What have you done, Katy? - It's over, so it doesn't matter.
別走
Please don't Leave!
發生什么事了
What happened?
你還是問問你老婆吧
Why don't you ask your wife?
你是相信我的  對吧
You do believe me, don't you?
你相信我絕不會做出那樣的事
You believe that I couldn't do something Like that?
當然  我相信你
Yeah. Course I do.
我就是個垃圾收集者  我什么也改變不了
I'm just a rubbish collector. I don't change anything.
我只能清理那些垃圾
I just sweep up the crap
而第二天它們又出現了
and the next day it's all just there again.
你做的事是重要的  它可以改變人們的生活
What you do is important. It makes a difference to people.
也是我當初愛上你的原因之一
It's one of the reasons I fell for you in the first place.
我只在乎他要對自己的行為負責任
All I care about is him answering for what he's done.
他們會找到證據  證明你強奸了我
They're gonna find proof that you raped me!
不  不會的  警探  不會的
No, you won't, Detective. No, you won't.
誰在撒謊
第一季第六集[本季終]
爸爸  怎么了
Dad? What's going on?
對不起  我沒想把你吵醒的
Ah, I'm sorry, mate. I didn't mean to wake you up.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
我告訴你也不會信的
You won't believe me if I told you.
這不重要
It's not important.
不過你只要知道
All you need to know is, though, er...
還沒有結束
it's not over.
-什么  -警察
- What? - The police.
我不明白  他們就是不肯放過我
I don't understand it, they just won't let it lie.
你的老師對我
It wasn't enough that your teacher
提出那種指控還不夠  現在警探...
made all those accusations against me, now the detective...
爸爸  出什么事了
Dad, what's going on?
警探也指控我
The detective is accusing me, too.
她說我攻擊了她
She's saying that I attacked her.
她說幾天前晚上
She's saying that a couple of nights ago
我闖進了她家
I broke into her house.
那太瘋狂了
That's crazy. I mean,
你已經證明尼爾森老師之前也撒過謊...
You already proved that Miss Nielson was lying before...
人們不能就這樣亂潑臟水  爸爸
People can't just go around saying this stuff, Dad.
這樣不對  告訴她上級
It's not right. Just tell her boss.
肯定有人能阻止這一切的
There must be someone who can make this stop.
警察只會護著自己人
The police, you see, they look after their own.
他們就是這樣
That's how they work.
不管她怎么說  他們都會信
Whatever she says, they'll back her up.
我們兩人只能各執一詞
It's just her word against mine.
我完蛋了
And I'll be destroyed.
除非
Unless er...
不知道  如果...也許如果
I don't know. What er... What if maybe er...
你告訴他們你看到過我
you told them that you saw me?
你想讓我對警察撒謊
You want me to lie to the police?
不不不  天啊  不是那樣的
No, no, no. God, nothing like that.
只是
Just erm...
我需要你的幫助  就像我
I need your help. You know, in the same way
幫你對付馬可達的爸爸那樣
that I helped you with Makeda's father?
那種善意的謊言
The kind of lie that's a good lie?
伙計
Look, mate...
我很不想這樣要你幫忙  好嗎
I feel sick to my stomach asking you, all right?
可我很害怕
But I'm afraid.
老實說  伙計  我真的很怕
To be honest with you, mate, I'm really scared.
他們要弄死我...
They want blood and...
他們...他們完全不會罷休
..They'll... they won't stop at anything.
天啊  如果我保護不了自己  誰來保護你
Christ, if I can't protect myself, who's gonna protect you?
天啊  對不起
Oh, God. I'm so sorry.
對不起  忘了我剛說的一切  好嗎
I'm so sorry, just forget that I asked, 0K?
忘了我的請求
Forget that I asked.
太尷尬了  原諒我
I'm so embarrassed. Please forgive me.
對不起那樣要求你  忘了吧
I'm so sorry that I asked, 0K? Just forget about it.
我到底怎么了  我都沒法...
Christ, what's happening to me? I can't even...
不管你需要什么  爸爸
Whatever you need, Dad.
不管你需要什么  我都會告訴他們
I'll tell them whatever you need.
我不會讓他們這么對你的
I'm not gonna let them do this to you.
謝謝你
Thank you.
天啊  謝謝你
Oh, my God, thank you.
謝謝你  伙計
Thanks, mate.
你為什么覺得這次會不一樣
What makes you think it'll be different this time?
你為什么覺得你能把他抓起來
What makes you think you can put him away?
讓我來操心安德魯·厄拉姆的事
You need to let me worry about Andrew Earlham.
-等你...  -等我們提出指控就給你電話
- Will you call me as soon as you - As soon as we press charges.
我保證
I promise.
好的
Ok.
三個月后
-旅途怎么樣  -很不錯  謝謝
- How was the journey down? - Good. Really easy. Thanks.
-你應該讓我來找你的  -不不不
- You really should have let me come to you. - Oh, no, no, no.
這里很不錯  我一直很想來這里
This is nice. I always wanted to come here.
你看上去不錯
You look good.
不是說你平時看上去不好
Not that you don't always look good.
謝謝
Thanks.
喝的
OK. Er, drinks.
你想喝點什么
What can I get you?
我去拿吧  如果你不介意的話
Actually, I'll get them, if you don't mind.
拜托  讓我去吧
Please. Let me.
好的
Ok.
去吧  跑跑跑跑跑
Go on. Run, run, run, run.
快跑
Run!
不不  你們別動
No, no, you're staying there.
孩子們來了  玩得開心嗎
Yeah, there's my boys. Did you have a good time?
你們玩得開心嗎
Did you have fun?
去吧  我燒好茶了
Go on, I've got tea ready for you.
我馬上就來
I'll be with you in a second.
他們一直問我會不會留下來
So they kept asking if I was going to stay.
是啊...
Well, it's er...
他們可能需要點時間習慣
it's gonna take some time for them to get used to it.
但他們會習慣的
But they will.
他們沒必要習慣
They don't have to.
是你的錯  凱蒂
You did this, Katy.
-不關別人的事  -我只想求你
- No-one else. - All I'm asking
我們為了他們試試
is that we try, for them.
我不想讓他們在成長的過程中
I don't want them growing
被我們兩邊拖拽
up being pulled in two different directions,
-夾在中間  -我也不想那樣
- caught in the middle - And I don't want that either.
但你的所作所為
But what you did...
我沒法忘記
I can't forget that.
也沒法原諒
Or forgive it.
爸爸來了
Daddy's coming.
周二見
See you on Tuesday.
我在地鐵上  給一位女士讓了座
So I was on the Tube and I offered my seat to this, erm, lady,
她問  為什么
and she said, 'Why?'
我說  因為你懷孕了
And I said, 'Well, because you're pregnant.'
-她說  我沒有懷孕  -天啊
- And she said, 'l'm not pregnant.' - Oh, my God.
-你說了什么  -我想不到該說什么
- What did you say? - I couldn't think of anything to say.
她看上去就像懷孕了
I mean, she looked pregnant.
肚子的形狀
From the shape of it.
我本來很確定...
l was really sure...
也許她只會覺得你很紳士
Maybe she just thought you were being chivalrous.
讓座給一個胖子嗎
By offering my seat to a fat person?
所以現在我只要在車上看到有人站著
So now whenever I'm on a train and I see someone standing,
我腦中就會浮現出無數想法
l have a million thoughts going through my head.
她們真的是懷孕了嗎  他們是不是沒那么老
Are they not actually pregnant? Are they not that old?
她們是不是女的
Are they not even a woman?
簡直是個雷區
It's a minefield.
這也太不公平了
It's not fair, though, is it?
你只是想做點好事  然后...
You were just trying to do something nice and...
怎么了  怎么回事
What? What is it?
怎么了  那是誰
What is it? Who is that?
勞拉  是他嗎
Laura, is that him?
這不重要
It doesn't matter.
天啊
Jesus.
他被二次調查了  對嗎
He was investigated a second time, right?
警察把他的生活翻了個底朝天  什么都沒發現
Police turned his life upside down and found precisely nothing.
他們就把他放了嗎
They just let him go?
就算哈蒙警長指控了他
Even after DI Harmon's charges,
他們也找不到抓他的證據
they couldn't find anything to put him away.
我想是因為他知道怎么銷毀證據吧
He knows how to cover his tracks, I suppose.
難以想象你看到他這樣逍遙法外的感受
I can't imagine what it must feel like to see him walking around.
我憤怒了很久  但是...
Well, I've been angry for long time, but erm...
這會消耗你
it wastes you.
會把你吞噬掉
It eats away at you and erm...
每當我有這種感覺時
Every time I feel that way,
感覺就像是事情再一次發生
it's like it's happening all over again,
所以在某一刻  不得不放手
so at some point you have to... let it go or...
或者至少試一試
try to, at least.
這杯敬你
Here's to you.
-還有多久  -一個月
- So how much longer? - A month.
-你找到新地方了嗎  -沒 很理智吧
- Have you found a new place yet? - No. Sensible, hey?
我只是覺得
I just felt like
離開這個鬼地方是當務之急
getting the hell out of this place was the priority,
但我看的所有房子
but everything I look at,
都不太好  要么太小  要么離公路太近
all I see is the bad stuff too small, too close to a road.
有個房子顏色太黃了
One place was too yellow.
那真不能要
That's a deal breaker.
謝謝你讓我過了一個愉快的夜晚
Thanks for a lovely night.
真的很高興跟你見面
Yeah, it was... it was really good seeing you.
抱歉  你一路送我回來
I'm sorry. You've come all this way
-而我卻不請你進屋  -不不  沒事
- and I'm not even inviting you in. - No, no, not at all.
那下周見
See you next week?
下周見
Next week it is.
晚安  伊恩
Good night, Ian.
晚安  勞拉
Good night, Laura.
就喝一杯  街角就有家很棒的小酒吧
One drink. There's a beautiful little pub just round the corner.
你現在已經和我約會這么多次了
You've been on enough dates with me now.
你覺得我這么容易被說服嗎
Do you think I'm easily persuaded?
至少我試了
At least I tried.
但下次吃晚飯  我堅持由我來做飯
But next time, dinner, I'll cook, I insist.
如果我做瑞士千層酥皮鮭魚
If I make my salmon en croute,
也許我兒子就會走開
maybe my son will bugger off.
也許我們就能單獨相處一會
We might have a moment to ourselves.
-那好吧  -太好了
- All right, then. - Yes.
晚安
Good night.
好了  晚安
OK, good night.
下次見
Till next time.
夏洛特  你好
Charlotte? Hi.
我叫勞拉·尼爾森
I'm Laura Nielson.
感謝你能來
I appreciate you coming.
你應該知道安德魯和我說起過你
You should know Andrew told me about you.
他怎么說的
What did he say exactly?
我第一次見他時  他就跟我說了
He told me, the first time I met him,
關于你給他帶來的那些麻煩
about all the trouble you'd caused him.
在那之后  他刪除了所有社交媒體賬號
He deleted all of his social media accounts after that,
用別名注冊了一個新賬戶
set up a new one under an alias
結果你還是找到了他
and yet you still found him.
還有我
And me.
我應該防著你嗎
Should I be worried about you?
安德魯·厄拉姆強奸了我
Andrew Earlham raped me.
強奸了一位名叫凡妮莎·哈蒙的警探
He raped a police officer called Vanessa Harmon,
在愛丁堡強奸了一位叫凱瑟琳·麥考利的女子
and he raped a woman called Catherine MacAulay in Edinburgh.
這是她們的號碼
Here are their numbers.
如果你不相信我  那就跟她們聊聊吧
If you don't believe me, then talk to them.
然后再作出判斷  你覺得誰說的是真話
Then you make up your mind who you think is telling the truth,
是我們三人  還是安德魯
the three of us or Andrew.
我不認識你  但是我知道他
Look, I don't know you, but I know him,
我知道他能做出些什么事
and I know what he's capable of.
他喜歡聰慧  獨立
He likes women who are smart, independent,
更有挑戰的女人
more of a challenge to control.
但愿你夠聰明  能多留點神
I'm hoping you're smart enough to watch your back.
或者至少
Or at least...
夠聰明地自己去查一查我跟你說的事
smart enough to check out what I'm telling you for yourself.
她真美
Aw. She's gorgeous.
-是嗎  -她甚至有你那種能看穿人的頭腦
- Is she? - Yeah, look, she's even got your see-through head.
如果是女孩的話
That's if she is a she.
你還好吧
Are you all right?
還好  我只是
Yeah, I'm just...
心不在焉
miles away.
我回來后  你一直這樣
You have been since I got back.
還有一次出差任務
Look, it's... it's one more tour of duty,
然后我就能回家了  不再是珍妮佛大兵了
and then I'm home, right? No more GI Jennifer.
分娩之前我會回來的  然后我哪也不去了
I'll be back before the birth and then I'm not going anywhere.
我只是想你了
Yeah. I just miss you, that's all.
你騙不了我  妮莎
You can't lie to me, Ness.
發生什么事了  你一臉愁容
What's going on? You've got that look.
-沒事  -聽著
- It's nothing. - Look,
我可以一直問到你受不了為止
I can keep asking you, again and again till I drive you crazy
或者你現在就告訴我
or you can just tell me now.
別問了  好嗎  我沒事
Just leave it, OK, I am fine.
你就告訴我吧
Just tell me.
妮莎
Ness...
你變了
you've changed.
你努力想要掩蓋  但是
You've tried to pretend, but...
但我知道
but I know what...
我只是想要聽實話
All I'm asking for is the truth.
是有其他人嗎
Is there someone else?
天  不是的  當然不是
God, no. Of course not.
那  到底怎么回事
Well, then, what is it?
你走的這些天里  發生了一些事  但拜托
While you were away, something happened, but please...
我不能  我不想說出口
please, I can't, I don't want to say it out loud.
不管是什么事  都沒事的
Whatever it is, it's OK.
你可以告訴我  怎么回事
You can tell me. You can tell me, what is it?
發生什么了
What is it?
告訴我
Just tell me.
盧克
Luke?
伙計
Hey, mate.
-你怎么樣  -挺好
- How are you doing? - Fine.
那就好
Good.
很好
That's good.
我想問問
I was wondering...
在學校還好嗎
..How's school, eh?
只是撤銷了指控
Just because the charges were dropped,
并不意味著人們不再討論了  是吧
doesn't mean people don't talk, right?
我知道這對你來說有多不難  但你這樣并不能
I know how hard it is for you but it's not gonna get any easier -
別給我什么建議了  爸爸
Spare me the advice, Dad.
就好像你有資格說這些話一樣
Like you're in any position.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你這話什么意思  盧克
What does that mean? Luke?
我洗清了罪名
I was cleared.
所有的罪名都洗得干干凈凈
All those charges, not one of them stuck.
要是你不相信我  好吧  你和我
If you don't believe me, right, you and me...
要是你
If you...
夏洛特  你好嗎
Charlotte. Hey. How are you?
慢點說  慢點說
Slow down, slow down.
什么
What?
她說了什么
What did she say?
安德魯·厄拉姆
你想怎樣
What do you want?
我想談談  勞拉  我還能想干什么
'I want to talk, Laura. What else would I want?'
你離我遠點
You need to leave me alone.
現在睡覺有點早  不是嗎
'Bit early to be in bed, isn't it?'
你說什么
What did you say?
你會想我嗎  當你躺在那的時候
'Do you think about me? When you're lying there.'
你肯定想起我了  不是嗎  盡管你不會承認
'You do, don't you? Even though you wouldn't admit it.'
你現在立刻給我離開這里
You need to get away from here right now.
我知道你和夏洛特聊過
'I know you spoke to Charlotte,
而且我覺得你才是那個該滾開的人
and I think you're the one that needs to back off.
我們是時候繼續自己的生活了  你不覺得嗎
Time we both got on with our lives, don't you think?'
你覺得你凌駕于所有人和事  是嗎
You think you stand above everyone and everything, don't you?
你覺得沒人抓得到你
That you're untouchable.
但你也只是個人罷了  安德魯
But you're just a man, Andrew.
一個惡心脆弱的人
A sick, weak man.
總有一天你會清醒過來
And one day you're gonna wake up
你造成的所有痛苦都將報復到你身上來
and all the pain you've caused is just gonna come back on you.
你聽起來很害怕  別怕
You sound scared. Don't be.
因為如果我想占有你
Cos if I wanted to have you...
再次占有你
again...
你不覺得只要我想  隨時都能動手嗎
don't you think I could have had you whenever I wanted?
-我要報警了  -你有沒有回想過那一晚
- I'm calling the police. - 'Do you ever think about that night?'
我知道我回想過
'I know I do.
有花朵圖案的床單  粉紅的枕套
The floral-patterned sheets, the pink pillowcases,
床上灰色的蓋毯
the grey throw on the bed,
肯定是幾周前剛換的
which couldn't have been more than a few weeks old.
其中一個商標
One of the tags was still
還掛在右下角
hanging from the bottom right-hand corner.
而你...躺在那兒
And you...lying there.
任由我擺布
Letting me do whatever I wanted.
我只要有機會就會重播  勞拉
I play that back, Laura, whenever I get the chance
好了  再見
All right, I'll see you soon.
-勞拉  -安德魯昨晚出現在了我家外面
- Laura? - Andrew turned up outside my house last night.
-什么  -是啊  但他什么都沒做
- What? - Yeah, he didn't do anything.
他只是想恐嚇我  而且他做到了
He just wanted to scare me, and it worked.
我整晚都沒睡
I couldn't sleep all night.
好的
OK.
我認為他把我們錄下來了
I think he filmed us.
他對我們做的那些事
What he did to us.
為什么這么說
Why would you say that?
他談到了那晚  談到了...
He talked about that night. He talked about erm...
墻上的一幅畫
a picture on my wall...
我床上很小的細節  那些瑣碎的小事
some tiny detail about my bed, little things...
他當時在我房間里不可能注意到那些
that he couldn't have noticed in the time he was in my room.
-他有時間四周打探  -他說...
- He had time to look around. - He said...
"我只要有機會就會重播"
"I play that back whenever I get the chance."
不是「我會回想」  而是「我會重播」
Not "I think about it", "I play it back."
可能只是一種說法
Could just be an expression.
他說的那些事  那些細節
The things he said, the detail he went into.
我跟你說  他都錄下來了
I'm telling you, he recorded it
而且那個令人作嘔的雜種把證據藏在某處
and the sick bastard still has it somewhere.
勞拉...
Laura...
他那樣的男人就是想控制和羞辱女性
Men like him want to control and humiliate women.
還有什么比錄下來更羞辱人的
What's more humiliating than a recording?
別說了  我們搜過他的家  工作地還有電腦
Stop. We searched his house, his work, his computer.
以及他的所有電子設備  好嗎
Every electronic device he has, OK?
-我們什么都沒找著  -我知道
- And we found nothing. - I know.
但他太狡猾了
But he's too smart for that.
勞拉  我需要你
Laura, what I need you to do
什么都不要去做  好嗎
is absolutely nothing, OK?
我可以派一輛巡邏警車守在你家外面
Now, I can get a patrol car to stay outside your house.
真棒  我所有問題都解決了
Great, all my problems are solved
聽著  你能至少把我說的那些話
Look, will you pass on what I've said at least?
轉達給你的那個同事嗎  只是...
To your colleagues. Just...
現在和他在一起的那個女人  夏洛特
That woman he's with now, Charlotte,
我希望她平安無事
I want her to be all right.
好的  我會跟他說的
Yeah, sure, I'll pass it on.
-你好  警探  -凡妮莎
- Hi, Detective - Vanessa.
-抱歉打擾了  -沒事  只是在趕些文書
- Sorry to bother you. - No bother. I'm catching up on paperwork.
我剛剛和勞拉·尼爾森通過電話了
I just spoke with Laura Nielson.
勞拉  我昨天見到她了
Laura, yeah, I met her yesterday.
她認為安德魯·厄拉姆錄下了他的罪行
She thinks Andrew Earlham records his attacks.
他把東西藏在了某個地方
That he's storing them somewhere.
厄拉姆昨晚出現在了她家外面
Earlham turned up outside her house last night.
他發現了她正在調查他
He found out she's been looking into him.
我知道
I know.
因為你告訴他的  為什么
Because you told him? Why?
我們要讓安德魯坐立不安  憤怒
We need Andrew unsettled. Angry.
那樣他就會犯錯  我們就可以把他繩之以法
That's when he'll make mistakes, that's when we'll catch him.
別擔心  我們在勞拉住的地方安排了巡邏車
Don't worry, we had a squad car on Laura's place.
你不應該讓她摻和進來的
You shouldn't put her in the middle of this.
是她自己摻和進來的
She put herself in the middle.
我只是抓住了機會給安德魯施壓
I just took the opportunity to push Andrew.
-抱歉  我知道我沒發言權  -你當然有
- I'm sorry, I know this isn't my place, but - Course it is.
這項行動多虧了你
This operation is down to you.
我只是希望能有更多證據上報
I just wish we had more to report.
-但今晚我要去他家吃完飯  -今晚
- But tonight I'm going for dinner at his place. - Tonight?
美妙周五夜  是吧
Great Friday night, huh
記住  別讓自己有機可乘
Remember, don't make yourself too available.
我看過資料了
I've read the profile.
-我只是提醒你  因為...  -我知道
- I'm only saying because... - Look, I know
等著批準通過很讓人泄氣
how frustrating it's been waiting for approval to come through
但我們成功在望了  有點信心
but we're close now. Just keep the faith.
好的
Ok.
-謝謝  警探  -沒事
- Thanks, Detective. - Of course.
-馬上就好  -我們需要你去五號檢查室
- Yep, just a minute. - OK, we need you in Exam 5.
我能先從柜子里拿點東西出來嗎
Can I grab something from my locker?
沒時間了  他們早就在等著了
There isn't much time. They've been waiting already.
好吧  咱們去把這個處理完
All right, then, let's get this over with.
很高興你給我打了電話
I'm glad you called.
我們好久都沒聯系了
It's been a long time.
是啊
Yeah.
給你
Er, here.
安德魯的手機
Andrew's phone.
謝謝
Thank you.
我會為你做任何事  你知道的
I'd do anything for you, you know that.
雖然你還在生我的氣
Even when you're angry at me.
我猜你也不會告訴我要這手機干什么
I don't suppose you're gonna tell me what that's for?
-你最好不要知道  -不要知道
- It's probably best that you don't know. - Don't know.
沒事
Ok.
我以為你已經釋懷了  勞拉
I thought you were moving on with your life, Laura.
-我必須這么做  -不  你不需要
- I have to do this. - No, you don't.
你從來都不需要做這些事
You never had to do any of it.
你經歷了噩夢般的事  你一直想糾正
You had a terrible thing happen to you and you tried to fix it.
而不是給自己點時間來恢復
Instead of taking time to get better and look after yourself.
我很想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
你覺得你會停止恨我嗎
Do you think you'll ever stop hating me?
我并不恨你  凱蒂
I don't hate you, Katy.
我只是...我沒法再相信你了
I just... I can't trust you.
我也不知道要怎么面對你
And I don't know how to be around you.
好吧...
Well...
等你準備好了
when you are ready...
...你知道我在哪
..You know where I am.
-快請進  -你好
- Hi, come in, come in. - Hey.
-謝謝  -就掛這吧
- Thanks. - There you go. Thank you.
你真美
Wow, you look amazing.
-從這里過去就好  -贊
- Just through here. - Great.
-挺香的啊  -謝謝夸獎
- That smells good. - Thank you.
也沒什么特別  就是一些專門訂購的食材
It's nothing much, just er, speciality-ordered ingredients
還為此準備了兩天
and about 48 hours of preparation.
-我很高興你能來  -為何不來
- I'm glad you came. - Why wouldn't I?
今天有人從我柜子里拿走了我的手機
Someone took my phone from a locker today.
-真煩人  -沒事  我把那個號取消了
- That's annoying. - No, it's fine, it's been cancelled,
我訂了另一支手機
and there's another one ordered.
你懂的  沒了手機就好像成了孩子
You know how it is - you lose your phone, you feel like a child.
不能發短信取消或修改時間
How did we ever make social arrangements
那我們要怎么約人
when we couldn't cancel or change with a text last-minute?
我只要答應了就會出現
Well, I like to turn up when I've agreed to.
我就是那么老套
I'm old-fashioned like that.
我也是
Me, too.
來點酒嗎  女士
Drink, m'lady?
好啊  聽起來不錯
Yeah. Sounds good.
-你這地方挺不錯的  -謝謝  還行吧
- I like your place. - Thanks. It's OK.
我一直想買些畫掛墻上  你知道嗎
Keep meaning to buy some more art to put on the walls, you know?
其實我上周買到了心儀的  是個本地的藝術家
I found something last week, actually. A local artist.
就在隔壁房的墻上  你有興趣可以去看看
It's on the wall in the other room, if you fancy.
當然
Sure.
冒昧問一下
Forgive me for asking. Er...
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
-當然  怎么了  -我不知道
- Of course. Why? - Oh, I don't know.
你...你有點不自在
You just... You seem tense.
有點累吧
Long day.
那我正好有你需要的東西
Then I have just the thing for you.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
抱歉  我能要杯水嗎  今天有點脫水
Sorry, could I get a glass of water? I'm a bit dehydrated today.
我不想讓你誤會
I don't want to start off on the wrong foot.
沒事  我馬上來
Yes, yes, of course. I'll be right back.
-給你  -謝謝
- There you go. - Thanks.
這畫真不錯  作者叫什么
It's a nice piece. What's the artist's name?
你包里的是什么  夏洛特
What's in your bag, Charlotte?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我看到你了
I saw you.
你看到我干什么  我不太懂
You saw me what? I don't understand.
你用注射器抽取了紅酒
You filled a syringe from your glass.
然后
And then...
我猜  你會編借口吧
You'll be making your excuses, I imagine.
一個緊急電話打來  然后你要先離開
An urgent phone call that meant you just had to leave
或者忽然頭很痛  然后...
or a sudden headache and then...
然后干什么呢
and then what?
把這珍貴的樣本送去警察實驗室嗎
Take your precious sample down to the police lab?
是這樣嗎
Is that about the size of it?
夏洛特
Charlotte?
讓開
Step away.
為什么
Why?
你覺得我會對你做什么
What is it you think I'm gonna do to you?
我可以立刻叫來后援
I can have back-up here in seconds.
我可沒阻止你離開
Well, I'm not stopping you from leaving.
你的實驗室不會發現任何東西的
Your lab's not gonna find anything.
我給你倒了杯紅酒  僅此而已
I poured you a glass of wine. And that's it.
真是可惜
It's a shame, really.
我們本可以很開心的
We'd have had fun.
我知道的
I know it.
該死  該死
Shit. Shit.
該死
Shit!
那么  這是什么原理
So, how does this work?
說實話  不知道
Honestly, no idea.
我技術小組的一個朋友給了我程序
A friend of mine from the tech squad just gave me the programme.
那你為什么要拿他的手機  為什么是現在
So, why did you take his phone, why now?
我覺得...
I think that erm...
當他強奸女人時候他會拍下來
when he rapes women he films it.
-你怎么知道的  -他說了一些話
- How do you know? - Something he said.
變態混蛋
Sick bastard.
我有機會的時候就該砸爛他的臉
I should've smashed his face in when I had the chance.
無論他把文件藏哪  都不在他家里
Wherever he keeps the files, they're not in his house,
也不在他的電腦和手機里
they're not on his computer or his phone,
警察肯定在哈蒙警長控告之后搜過了
the police would have searched after DI Harmon's charge.
所以如果他有記錄  多半在其他地方
So if he keeps recordings, they're offsite?
他這種人  肯定會很小心
Someone like him, he will be careful.
會有很多要梳理的東西
There'll be a lot to get through.
我可以把手機的內容傳到電腦上
I could dump the contents of the phone onto the laptop.
-我們可以一起看  -我知道我不該請你幫忙
- we can both look. - I know I shouldn't be asking you for help, it's...
上次就是因為幫助我才讓你變成現在這樣
helping me last time that got you into this situation.
別  是安德魯最終害我丟了工作
Nah, Andrew was the one who made sure I lost my job.
好吧  那么...
Right. Well...
好  感謝你打電話來
OK. Thanks for calling.
行動不順利
The op went badly.
針對安德魯·厄拉姆的臥底行動
The undercover with Andrew Earlham.
有多遭
How bad?
天啊  沒事的  我們會找到其他辦法
Jesus. It's OK, we're gonna find another way.
怎么找
How?
他逃脫了上一個指控
He walked away from the last accusation.
現在是你  還需要多少人才能阻止他
And now you. How many more until somebody stops him?
我們在盡力  我是說  羅里
We're doing our best. I mean, Rory...
-整個團隊  所有人  -顯然還不夠好
- the whole team, everybody. - Well, it's not good enough.
他在我們家里襲擊了你  他需要面對后果
He attacked you in our house. He needs to face the consequences.
-冷靜  珍  -我不能  這事...
- Calm down, Jen. - I can't. It's...
我知道事情發生在你身上而不是我
I know this happened to you and not me,
但我感覺保護你是我的職責
but I feel like it's my job to protect you,
-而我卻沒在  -請不要這么說  不要
- and I wasn't there. - Please don't say that. You mustn't.
珍
Jen.
安德魯有沒有提到過一個叫
Did Andrew ever mention anybody called...
-米婭·蘭斯夫卡的人  -沒有  怎么了
- Mia Lentzovka? - No. Why?
不知道呢  這里有個幾天前的消息
Dunno. There's a text message from a few days ago.
所以警察肯定沒看到
So the cops wouldn't have seen it.
「你什么時候能來拿你的東西」
"When can you come over to collect your things?"
有這個女人的地址嗎
Is there an address for this woman?
-有  在聯絡簿里  -太好了  謝謝你
- Yeah, it's in the contacts. - Brilliant. Thank you.
好了  我要給凡妮莎打電話
Right. I'm gonna call Vanessa.
我希望這能有用
I hope it's useful.
謝謝
Thanks.
我真的很抱歉
I really am sorry.
關于我和凱蒂的事
About me and Katy.
我知道  我也是
I know. Me too.
謝謝你幫我
Thanks for helping me.
「你好  我是凡妮莎·哈蒙
'Hi, this is a Vanessa Harmon.
我現在不在  請留言」
I'm not around right now, so leave a message.
你好
Hello.
需要幫助嗎
Can I help you?
你好  我是...
Hi, I'm a...
安德魯的朋友
a friend of Andrew's.
安德魯·厄拉姆
Andrew Earlham.
-他沒事吧  -挺好的  他沒事
- Is he all right? - Fine. Yeah, yeah, fine.
你是米婭嗎
Erm, are you Mia?
是的  是我
Yes. I am.
我是勞拉
I'm Laura.
實際上  我能進去聊幾分鐘嗎
Actually, is it all right if I come in for a minute?
謝謝
Thanks.
西爾維婭
Sylvia?
這是安德魯的朋友  勞拉
This is a friend of Andrew's. Laura.
你好  親愛的
Hello, dear.
能有訪客真好
How nice to have a visitor.
安德魯從來不帶客人來  是吧  米婭
Andrew never brings visitors here, does he, Mia?
-從來沒  -安德魯叫我來幫他取東西
- No, never. - Andrew asked me to pick something up for him.
他有東西存在這里嗎
He's got some stuff stored here?
他本應該幾天前來拿的
He was supposed to collect it a few days ago.
是的
Yes.
是的  當然
Yes, of course.
請跟我來
Please, follow me.
謝謝
Thanks.
請吧
Here you go.
謝謝  我會盡量快點
Thanks. I'll try and be quick.
喂  我是米婭
Hello. It's Mia.
-你找到了嗎  你有沒有...  -有  謝謝
- Do you have everything? Did you find - Yes, thanks.
我得走了  謝謝你們
I've got to run. Thank you.
凡妮莎
-她在里邊很生氣  -好吧
- She's pretty upset in there. - OK.
-天啊  終于  -真抱歉
- Oh, God. Finally. - I'm sorry.
我沒值班  我得走程序進來
I wasn't on duty. I had to get in.
我給凡妮莎打電話卻直接進語音信息了
I called Vanessa but her phone goes straight to voicemail.
我還以為有了這發現  你們會行動快一些
You'd think people would move quicker after what I found.
前臺告訴我錄像的事了
The front desk told me about the recordings.
是啊  那個...
Yeah, it's erm...
是...
Yeah, erm...
我都沒膽量去看  但是...
I could barely bring myself to look, but...
但我在里邊  還有凡妮莎  還有...
But I'm in there, and...Vanessa and...
我算了算  至少還有其他15個人
I counted at least 15 others.
15位和我有同樣遭遇的女人
15 women just like me.
17.
技術人員說是17位
The tech guys tell me 17.
而且安德魯·厄拉姆可以很清晰地被辨認出
And Andrew Earlham is clearly identifiable.
他將會進去很長時間  尼爾森小姐
He's going away, Miss Nielson, for a really, really long time.
我之前也聽過這話
I've heard that before.
他們讓你進了房子  他們讓你搜索小屋
They let you into the house. They let you search the shed.
你找到的一切都會成為證據
Everything you found is going into evidence.
我向你保證
I promise you.
已經結束了
It's over now.
結束了
It's over.
我們現在正去抓捕他
We're picking him up right now.
我們要找安德魯·厄拉姆
We're looking for Andrew Earlham.
-找我爸爸干什么  -我們有逮捕令
- What do you want with my dad? - We have a warrant for his arrest.
他不在這里
He's not here.
強奸嫌疑犯
警察尋求幫助尋找肯特強奸嫌疑犯
最后  雖然進行了三周的搜尋
'And, finally, despite three weeks of searching,
警察依然無法找到安德魯·厄拉姆
the police are no closer to finding Andrew Earlham,
此人與多項強奸指控有關
who is wanted in connection with a number of rape allegations.
厄拉姆先生  廣山醫院的心胸外科醫生
Mr Earlham, a cardiothoracic surgeon at Broadhill Hospital,
是近幾個月
has been the subject of
兩起調查的主要對象
two separate investigations in recent months,
但是都沒有最終定罪
but neither case led to prosecution.
幾周前發布了一張針對厄拉姆先生的逮捕令
'Several weeks ago, a warrant was issued for Mr Earlham's arrest
之后不久  他幾年前性侵對象的錄像
and, shortly after, recordings of his alleged sexual assaults
被泄露給了媒體
dating back years, were leaked to the press.
警方尋求任何線索 只要關于厄拉姆先生
'Police ask that anyone with information on Mr Earlham
或是他目前的所在
or his whereabouts come forward.'